Finding Aid for the Akira Togawa Papers LSC.1711
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Postwar Publications
  - H. Miscellaneous
    - Makida Kozo [characters], Mukuteki [characters], Los Angeles: Rafu Shoten,; Matsumoto Motomitsu [characters], Fukko Senjo ni Odoru Kikan Doho [characters], Los Angeles: Rafu Shoten, 1961 1949. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Nagumo Shoji [characters], Gadena Goroku [characters], Los Angeles: Nanka Teiengyo Remmei,; Takeshita Tomasu [characters], Yamato Damashii to Seijoki [characters], Tokyo: Sanno Shobo,; Uegurin Michiko [characters], Amerika Kyosei Shuyojo: Kutsujoku ni Taeta Nikkeijin [characters], Tokyo: Seiji Koho Senta, 1959 1967 1974. (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Yaguchi Sachie [characters], Neko to Futari [characters], Tokyo: Nihon Seikokai Shuppan Jigyobu,; Yamada Kozo [characters], Issei Shageki [characters], Los Angeles: Rafu Shimposha,; Yoneda Karu [characters], Zaibei Nihonjin Rodosha no Rekishi [characters], Tokyo: Shin Nihon Shinsho, 1974 1938 1967. (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous program copies. (Box 32, Folder 3-4)
- Works of Japanese Poets and Writers
  - A. Ogiwara Seisensui [characters]
    - Basho Fukei [characters], Tokyo: Shunjusha,; Basho Junrei [characters], Tokyo: Shunjusha, 1955 1955. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Basho Meiku [characters], Tokyo: Shakai Shiso Kenkyukai,; Basho Shunju [characters], Tokyo: Shunjusha, 1957 1956. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Basho wo Tazunete [characters], Tokyo: Shunjunsha,; Basho wo Tazunete [characters], Kyoto: Gasendo, 1955 1968. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Basho Buson Shiki [characters], Tokyo: Gengensha,; Basho Zuihitsu: Haru wa Akebono [characters], Tokyo: Usui Shobo, 1955 1948. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Choryu [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha, 1964. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Daiko [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha, 1971. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Gensen [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha, 1960. (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Haiku to Seinen [characters], Tokyo, Chobunkaku,; Hawai Nikki [characters], Tokyo: Daisenen, 1943 1937. (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Ichifuji [characters], Tokyo: Sakurai Shoten,; Issa Meiku [characters], Tokyo: Shakai Shiso Kenkyukai, 1943 1959. (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Jinsei Dokuhon [characters], Tokyo: Jitsugyo no Nihonsha,; Jiyuritsu Haiku Hyoshaku [characters], Tokyo: Hibonkaku, 1962 1938. (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Kaki to Momo [characters], Kyoto: Yashiro Shoten,; Kenchinjiru [characters], Tokyo: Shinse Shobo, 1946 1956. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Nihon Saiji Kiko [characters], Tokyo: Shudosha,; Oku no Hosomichi no Kokoro [characters], Tokyo: Shunjusha, 1960 1956. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Oku no Hosomichi no Michi [characters], Tokyo: Shunjusha,; Oku no Hosomichi wo Tazunete [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha, 1955 1936. (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Editor, Ozora: Ozaki Hosai Shu [characters], Tokyo: Shunjusha,; Seisensui Kushu [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,; Senriko [characters], Tokyo: Kobunsha, 1956 1936 1946. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Shikai [characters], Tokyo: Bunka Hyoron Shuppansha,; Soko Nikki [characters], Tokyo: Daisenen, 1976 1937. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Editor, Soun [characters], January-December 1956. (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Soun [characters], January-December 1957. (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Soun [characters]:, April-August & October-December 1964; and January-March 1965. (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Soun [characters], January-December 1966. (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Soun [characters], January-December 1967. (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Soun [characters], January-November 1968. (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Soun [characters]:, February 1969; April 1970; September 1972; and May 1978. (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Soun Daijuni Kushu [characters], Tokyo: Sounsha,; Soun Dainijuni Kushu [characters], Tokyo: Sounsha, 1937 1951. (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Soun Dainijusan Kushu [characters], Tokyo: Sounsha,; Soun Dainijugo Kushu [characters], Tokyo: Sounsha, 1952 1955. (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Soun Dainijushichi Kushu [characters], Tokyo: Sounsha,; Soun Dainijuhachi Kushu [characters], Tokyo: Sounsha, 1957 1958. (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Soun Dainijuku Kushu [characters], Tokyo: Sounsha,; Soun Daisanju Kushu [characters], Tokyo: Sounsha, 1959 1960. (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Soun Daisanjuichi Kushu [characters], Tokyo: Sounsha,; Soun Daisanjuni Kushu [characters], Tokyo: Sounsha, 1961 1962. (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Soun Daisanjusan Kushu: Nikko Gekkoshu [characters], Kamakura: Daisenen,; Soun Daisanjuyon Kushu [characters], Kamakura: Daisenen, 1963 1964. (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Soun Daisanjugo Kushu [characters], Kamakura: Daisenen,; Soun Daisanjuroku Kushu [characters], Kamakura: Daisenen, 1965 1967. (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Soun Daisanjushichi Kushu [characters], Kamakura: Daisenen,; Soun Daisanjuhachi Kushu [characters], Kamakura: Daisenen,; Soun no Michi [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha, 1969 1971 1955. (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Soun Sakuhinsen Daiichi [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha, 1963. (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Soun Sakuhinsen Daini [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha, 1966. (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Tabibito Basho [characters], Tokyo: Shunjusha,; Tozai Nanboku [characters], Tokyo: Sakurai Shoten, 1955 1931. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Watakushi no Tsuzurikata [characters], Tokyo: Kobunsha,; Zoku Tabibito Basho [characters], Tokyo: Shunjusha, 1946 1955. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Editor, Zui [characters]:, January-September & November-December 1959; February 1962; and January-December 1963. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Zui [characters]:, January-December 1964; and January-December 1965. (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Zui [characters]:, January-December 1966; September 1967; January-September 1968; and September 1971. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Inoue Mikio [characters], editor, Jiyuritsu Haiku no Michi: Ogiwara Seisensui to Sono Monkatachi [characters], n.p.,; Ogiwara Seisensui, Watanabe Koin, Taidan: Ichigo Ichie no Watashi wo Ikiru [characters], Shobo [characters], no. 5, 1966 (1974). (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Sounsha [characters], editor, Soun Ichinin Jukkushu Daini [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha, 1968. (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Sounsha [characters], editor, Soun Ichinin Jukkushu Daisan [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha, 1970. (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Sounsha [characters], Soun Techo [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha,; Sounsha [characters], Soun Shayu Meibo [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha, 1955 1963. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - B. Oyama Sumita [characters]
    - Daichowa [characters], Tokyo: Aporonsha,; Daigo no Hitobito [characters], Ehime: Daikosha, 1960 1950. (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Editor, Daiko [characters]:, November 1961; June 1963; December 1965; and March 1968. (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Daiko [characters]:, September 1968; January & April-December 1970; and January-April 1971. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Daiko [characters], May-June & August-November 1971. (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Editor, Gochu Nikki [characters], Tokyo: Aporonsha,, vols. 1-5., 1958-64 (Box 41, Folder 3-5)
    - Gojunen [characters], Ehime: Daikosha,; Haijin Santoka no Shogai [characters], Tokyo: Aporonsha, 1975 1957. (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Hannya Shingyo no Hanashi [characters], Kyoto: Higeen,; editor, Hyohaku no Haijin: Santoka no Shuki [characters], Tokyo: Chobunsha, 1967 1968. (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Jigazo: Santoka [characters], Ehime: Daikosha,; Jinsei Hyakuso [characters], Ehime: Daikosha, 1966 1969. (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Jinsei no Bi [characters], Ehime: Daikosha,; Kannonkyo no Hanashi [characters], Kyoto: Higeen, 1961 1962. (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Kannonkyo no Hanashi to Seigoku Junrei [characters], Tokyo: Higeen,; Kono Michi [characters], Tokyo: Yoshikawa Shobo, 1971 1975. (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Nekorobigusa [characters], Ehime: Daikosha,; Nihon no Aji [characters], Ehime: Daikosha, 1957 1967. (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Nihon no Tabi [characters], Tokyo: Aporonsha,; Ohara Yugaku Monogatari [characters], Chiba: Beibon Toshokan, 1960 1956. (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Ryokan Monogatari [characters], Tokyo: Aporonsha,; Ryokuin ni Kataru Zen [characters], Tokyo: Yoshikawa Shobo, 1966 1972. (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Editor, Sanson Nikki: Oka Rakuboku [characters], Ehime: Daikosha,; With Takato Takema [characters], Santoka: Ku to Kotoba [characters], Tokyo: Shuyodo Shoten, 1969 1974. (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Santoka no Shogai [characters], Ehime: Santoka Kenshokai,; Santoka no Yado: Soshite Sake to Mizu to [characters], Tokyo: Yayoi Shobo,; editor, Santoka Zenshu [characters], Tokyo: Shuyodo,, vol. 1., n.d. 1976 1972 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Editor, Sobokuto: Santoka [characters], Ehime: Daikosha,; Sobokuto [characters], unpublished manuscript,; Wasureenu Hitobito [characters], Ehime: Daikosha, 1956 1940 1954. (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Zazen Gojunen [characters], Tokyo: Yayoi Shobo,; Zazen Nyumon [characters], Kyoto: Higeen, 1977 1965. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - C. Uchijima Hokuro [characters]
    - Aruya Nashiya [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha,; Dochu Zakki [characters], Nagano: Uchijima Hokuro, 1966 1949. (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Hokuro Sakuhin Kinenshu [characters], Kyoto: Uchijima Hokuro, 1971. (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Kochu Zuihitsu [characters], Kyoto: Uchijima Hokuro,; Kumo to Doro [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha, 1954 1962. (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Mimizu no Fun [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha,; Rakuyaki: Tsukurikata, Ajiwaikata [characters], Osaka: Sogensha, 1963 1958. (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Shippo [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha,; Shunpu Shuu [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha, 1969 1971. (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Tobo [characters], Kyoto: Kuwana Bunseido,; Toko no Rakusho [characters], Tokyo: Shunjusha, 1942 1966. (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Tsuchi wa Ikite Iru [characters], Kamakura: Sounsha, 1960. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - D. Yoshikawa Eiji [characters]
    - Doka Musume wo Tanomimasu [characters], Tokyo: Rokko,; Edo Chokonka [characters], Tokyo: Genrisha, 1969 1948. (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Harusame Yubin [characters], Tokyo: Hayakawa Shobo,; Kankanmushi wa Utau [characters], Tokyo: Hayakawa Shobo, 1947 1947. (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Kuroda Nyosui [characters], Tokyo: Rokko Shuppansha,; Oriori no Shirushi [characters], Tokyo: Rokko Shuppansha, 1951 1953. (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Shin Taishu Bungaku Zenshu: Saijoki [characters], Tokyo: Hibonkaku,, vol. 1; Wasurenokori no Ki: Shihan Jijoden [characters], Tokyo: Bungei Shinju Shinsha, 1947 1957. (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Yoshikawa Eiji Taiwashu [characters], Tokyo: Kodansha,; Yoshikawa Eiji Zenshu: Edojo Shinju Sakebu Raicho [characters], Tokyo: Kodansha,, vol. 7., 1967 1969 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Zuihitsu Shin Heike [characters], Tokyo: Asahi Shimbunsha, 1958. (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - E. Works on Yoshikawa Eiji
    - Kokumin Bunka Shinkokai [characters], Yoshikawa Eiji Ten [characters], Tokyo: Kodansha, 1967. (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Yoshikawa Eimei [characters], Chichi Yoshikawa Eiji [characters], Tokyo: Bunka Shuppankyoku,; Watakushi no Yoshikawa Eiji Kanko Iinkai [characters], Watakushi no Yoshikawa Eiji: Sono Shokan to Tsuioku [characters], Tokyo: Bungei Shunju Shinsha, 1974 1962. (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - F. Maeda Tetsunosuke [characters]
    - Rogi Dai-Rokushu: Shiyosha Soritsu Yonjushunen Kinen Maeda Tetsunosuke Tokushu [characters],; editor, Shiyo [characters], no. 227, December 1963 (June 1961). (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Shiyo [characters], no. 245, no. 262 & no. 264, (April 1966) (October 1970) (November 1971). (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Shiyo [characters], no. 265 no. 283 & no. 287; editor, Shiyo Shijin Senshu Dai-Nikan [characters], Tokyo: Shiyosha, (February 1972), (August 1976) (October 1977) 1954. (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Editor, Shiyo Shijin Senshu Dai-Sankan [characters], Tokyo: Shiyosha,; Yama no Shishu [characters], Tokyo: Meibundo, 1967 1959. (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - G. Yoshino Hideo [characters]
    - Yoshino Hideo Kashu [characters], Tokyo: Yayoi Shobo,; Yawaraka na Kokoro [characters], Tokyo: Kodansha, 1967 1966. (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - H. Yoshino Tomiko [characters]
    - Koto wa Shizuka ni [characters], Tokyo: Yayoi Shobo,; Wagamune no Sokohi ni [characters], Tokyo: Yayoi Shobo, 1976 1978. (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - I. Yagi Jukichi [characters]
    - Shikamado Norio [characters], Yagi Jukichi Shigatami Inori [characters], Tokyo: Hobunkan Shuppan,; Tanaka Kiyomitsu [characters], Shijin Yagi Jukichi [characters], Tokyo: Mugi Shobo, 1968 1969. (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Yagi Jukichi et al. [characters], Kokoro no Uta [characters], Tokyo: Doshinsha, 1967. (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Yagi Jukichi [characters], Yagi Jukichi Shishu [characters], Tokyo: Yayoi Shobo, 1958. (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Yoshino Tomiko and Tanaka Kiyomitsu [characters], editors, Yagi Jukichi Mihappyo Iko to Kaiso [characters], Tokyo: Mugi Shobo, 1971. (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - J. Takeuchi Teruko [characters]
    - Hana to Menoko to [characters], Tokyo: Daini Shobo,; Inochi Atarashi [characters], Tokyo: Shufu no Tomo Sha, 1958 1952. (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Kizu no Naka no Seishun [characters], Tokyo: Jitsugyo no Nihonsha,; Kono Namida wo Asu ni Nokoshite [characters], Tokyo: Bancho Shobo,; Shizukanaru Ai [characters], Tokyo: Daiichi Shobo, 1957 1966 1939. (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - K. Other Poets and Authors
    - Akiyama Kodo [characters], Sumi no Uta [characters], Tokyo: Fuji Tankidai Shuppanbu, 1977. (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Akiyama Shukoryo [characters], Baika Mugen [characters], Tokyo: Soshunkukai,; Akiyama Shukoryo [characters], Haiku Hyogenron [characters], Kanagawa: Sounsha, 1965 1958. (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Bungeika Kyokai [characters], editor, Shi to Zuihitsu Shu [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,, vols. 1 & 2., 1927 & 1928 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Daito Jiro [characters], Gendai Shijin Sosho: Seio wo Iku [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,, vol. 18; Enomoto Eiichi [characters], Gunjokai [characters], Osaka: Higashi Hongwanji Nanpa Betsuin, 1925 1974. (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Fujioka Masaichi et al. [characters], editor, Hekigoto [characters], Matsuyama: Midori Godo no Kai,; Fujishima Udai [characters], editor, Miyazawa Kenji Shishu [characters], Tokyo: Daiwa Shob,; Fukao Sumako [characters], Gendai Shijin Sosho: Hanmyo [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,, vol. 17., 1953 1966 1925 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Fukuda Masao [characters], Kogen no Shojo [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,; Hagiwara Sakutaro [characters], Gendai Shijin Sosho: Cho wo Yumemu [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,, vol. 14., 1926 1923 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Hashida Tosei [characters], Masaoka Shiki Kashu [characters], Tokyo: Kogyokudo Shoten,; Hinatsu Konosuke [characters], Gendai Shijin Sosho: Kofu na Tsuki [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,, vol. 10., 1924 1922 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Ishihara Hirobumi [characters], Bohemian Purofiru [characters], Tokyo: Shijin Jidaisha,; Itaguchi Tomiko [characters], Seiryu [characters], Tokyo: Miyazawa Kenji Kenkyukai, 1931 1960. (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Ito Toichi [characters], editor, Gendai Tanka Kansho [characters], Tokyo: Daini Shobo,, vol. 1; Kaneko Mitsuharu [characters], Gendai Shijin Sosho: Mizu no Ruro [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,, vol. 20., 1951 1926 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Kawaji Ryuko [characters], Gendai Shijin Sosho: Yogen [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,, vol. 3; Kimata Osamu [characters], editor, Hakushu no Uta [characters], Tokyo: Shakai Shisosha, 1922 1966. (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Kitahara Hakushu [characters], Hakushu Doyoshu [characters], Tokyo: Arusu,, vol. 1; Kitahara Hakushu [characters], Hakushu Shishu [characters], Tokyo: Arusu,, vol. 1., 1924 1920 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Kitahara Hakushu [characters], Hakushu Shishu [characters], Tokyo: Arusu,, vol. 2; Kitahara Hakushu [characters], Nihon Shijin Zenshu: Kitahara Hakushu [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,, vol. 7., 1920 1966 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Kondo Yoshimi [characters], editor, Chugoku Kadan Senshu [characters], Hiroshima: Chugoku Shimbunsha Bunkakyoku Shuppanka,; Kubota Utsubo [characters], Takujo no Tomoshibi [characters], Tokyo: Hasegawa Shobo, 1959 1955. (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Kumagai Tetsutaro [characters], Hakumei no Kioku [characters], Tokyo: Heibonsha,; Masatomi Oyo [characters], Gendai Shijin Sosho: Sekai no Minshu ni [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,, vol. 16., 1960 1925 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Matsuoka Kazue [characters], Sato no Ko Nikki [characters], Tokyo: Matsuoka Kazue,; Matsuoka Kazue [characters], Zakuroishi [characters], Tokyo: Matsuoka Kazue, 1973 1972. (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Miyahara Shin [characters], Chikurin Raisan [characters], Takarazuka: Miyahara Masayo, 1972. (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Miyahara Shin [characters], Tetsujin Yamada Hokoku: Sono Hito to Shi [characters], Tokyo: Meitoku Shuppansha,; Miyahara Shin [characters], Tetsujin Yamada Hokoku to Sono Shi [characters], Tokyo: Meitoku Shuppansha, 1976 1978. (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Miyazaki Joji [characters], Miyazaki Joji Zen Shishu [characters], Tokyo: Furukawa Shobo,; Momoda Soji [characters], Gendai Shijin Sosho: Kazaguruma [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,, vol. 9; Momoda Soji [characters], Shizukanaru Toki [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha, 1974 1922 1925. (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Nakagawa Soen [characters], Meihen [characters], Tokyo: Kokudosha,; Nakamura Rokuro [characters], editor, Haijin Issa [characters], Tokyo: Kobunsha, 1949 1933. (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Nakatsuka Ippekiro [characters], Ippekiro Kusho [characters], Tokyo: Privately printed,; Noguchi Yonejiro [characters], Sanjo ni Tatsu [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha, 1948 1923. (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Noguchi Yonejiro [characters], Watakushi wa Gendai Fukei wo Kiru [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,; Otsuki Miyoshi [characters], Hakuboku no Kona [characters], Tokyo: Kogyokudo Shoten, 1927 1927. (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Saigusa Joban [characters], Kai no Sora [characters], Tokyo: Ichiro Kai,; Sakamura Shinmin [characters], Haru no Izumi [characters], Ehime: Tanpopo no Kai, 1960 1959. (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Sakamura Shinmin [characters], Ho [characters], Tokyo: Daito Shuppansha,; Sato Sonosuke [characters], Gendai Shijin Sosho: Kisetsu no Basha [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,, vol. 5., 1971 1922 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Senke Motomaro [characters], Gendai Shijin Sosho: Enten [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,, vol. 7; Shimoda Korenao [characters], Mune yori Mune ni [characters], Tokyo: Koransha, 1923 1923. (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Tada Fuji [characters], Gendai Shijin Sosho: Yoru no Ichibu [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,, vol. 19; Takamura Kotaro [characters], Atorie Nite [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha, 1926 1956. (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Takamura Kotaro [characters], Chieko Sho [characters], Tokyo: Ryuseikaku,; Takamura Kotaro [characters], Chieko Sho Sono Go [characters], Tokyo: Ryuseikaku, 1940 1950. (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Taketomo Sofu [characters], Shishu [characters], Tokyo: Shinchosha,; Togawa Tsuguo [characters], Gerutsuen to Roshia Shakai [characters], Tokyo: Ochanomizu Shobo, 1926 1973. (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Togawa Tsuguo [characters], trans., Mukogishi Kara: Gerutsuen [characters], Tokyo: Gendai Shichosha,; Togawa Tsuguo [characters], Sekai no Rekishi: Roshia to Sorenpo [characters], Tokyo: Kodansha,, vol. 18., 1970 1978 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Togawa Tsuguo [characters], trans., Sekai wo Tsukutta Hitobito: Torusutoi: Jindoshugi ni Ikita Sekai no Bungo [characters], Tokyo: Heibonsha, 1978. (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Uriu Toshikazu [characters], Myoko Haijin Ryokuhei-san [characters], Tokyo: Shunyodo Shoten,; Wada Akitoshi [characters], Dai Hachi Kushu Koun [characters], Tokyo: Privately printed, 1973 1970. (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Watanabe Junzo [characters], Seikatsu wo Utau [characters], Tokyo: Kogyokudo Shoten,; Watanabe Satoru [characters], Nenrin [characters], Tokyo: Watanabe Satoru, 1926 1975. (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Yoshino Nobuo [characters], editor, Gendai Nihon Shishu [characters], Tokyo: Shijin Jidaisha,; Yoshino Nobuo [characters], editor, Gendai Nihon Shishu [characters], Tokyo: Gendai Shobo, 1933 1934. (Box 55, Folder 5)
- Newspaper Clippings Albums, 1952-1978
  - Scrapbook 1, 1953-62. (Box 56)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1962-65. (Box 56)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1965-66. (Box 57)
  - Scrapbook 4, 1967-68. (Box 57)
  - Scrapbook 5, 1971-72. (Box 58)
  - Scrapbook 6, 1976-78. (Box 58)